<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Handling on </title>
    <link>/categories/data-handling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Handling on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-UK</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/data-handling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading, Merging and Joining Several Datasets - PostgreSQL EDT</title>
      <link>/2019/08/loading-merging-and-joining-datasets-postgresql-edt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/loading-merging-and-joining-datasets-postgresql-edt/</guid>
      <description>This is the coding necessary to assemble the various data feeds and sort out the likes of variables naming &amp;amp; new features creation plus some general housekeeping tasks.
In order to simulate normal working conditions I would face if the data was stored on a database, I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded the excel files onto a local PostgreSQL database that I&amp;rsquo;ve created on my machine. I am going to go through the steps I followed to set up a connection between RStudio and said database and extract the information I needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading, Merging and Joining Several Datasets - Excel EDT</title>
      <link>/2019/07/loading-merging-and-joining-datasets-excel-edt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/07/loading-merging-and-joining-datasets-excel-edt/</guid>
      <description>This is the minimal coding necessary to assemble various data feeds and sort out the likes of variables naming &amp;amp; new features creation plus some general housekeeping tasks. It includes general housekeeping tasks like shortening variables names to ease visualisations, creating essential new features and sorting out variables order
The Dataset library(tidyverse) library(lubridate) library(readr)  The dataset I&amp;rsquo;m using here accompanies a Redbooks publication called Building 360-Degree Information Applications which is available as a free PDF download.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>